flyporter.com 2017-08-02

# Privacy Policy | Porter Airlines

Breadcrumb menus

## PORTER AIRLINES' COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY

Porter Airlines Inc. (“Porter” or “we” or “us”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers (“You”). This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes Porter’s personal information privacy policies and practices with respect to the collection, use and disclosure of Your personal information. Our obligations and Your rights are subject to applicable legislation, including the terms of the **Personal Information Protection and Electronics Documents Act and Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation (CASL)**.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal information is any information about an identifiable individual, such as Your name, email address, mailing addresses, financial information, travel document details, citizenship, gender, date of birth, information collected electronically through Porter’s web site at www.flyporter.com (“Web Site”) and any other information that identifies who You are. Personal information about You may be collected by Porter directly or provided to Porter by third parties, such as travel agents or a credit card company.

## WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES PORTER COLLECT ?

Porter limits the collection and use of Your information to the minimum we require to deliver requested information, products or services to You. We will keep Your information only for as long as it is reasonably needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. We may also collect personal information about You from our service providers.

If You would like to make a reservation or purchase (directly with Porter by telephone, online through the Web Site or through a travel agency or other third party), sign up to a mailing list or program, enter a contest, apply for a job, or request some other information or service that may be offered by Porter from time to time, You will be required to provide certain personal information as is described in this Policy. Requested information may include Your name, address, telephone number, gender, email address, credit card number and expiry date. Requested information is required in order to identify You, in order to contact You, if necessary, and to complete Your purchase or request.

If You request a special service, we need to collect additional personal information in order to facilitate Your request:

### Travel Documents

In order to access airport facilities and permit You to board an aircraft You will be required to provide personal identification documents, (including as may be required by applicable law and airline and airport security requirements) including specified picture identification. Such information is collected for security, legal and identification purposes and is generally returned to You immediately and not retained by Porter.

### Infants

Porter is pleased to offer free travel to infants under two (2) years of age (without a dedicated seat). In order to confirm the eligibility of Your infant and ensure that Your infant’s ticket is correctly processed we need to record Your infant’s date of birth at the time of booking. At the airport, for verification, You will be required to present identification verifying Your infant’s date of birth. If Your travel includes a transfer from Porter to another airline Your infant’s date of birth may also be transferred to that other airline.

### Special Services and Assistance and Unaccompanied Minors

Porter is pleased to offer certain special travel services to individuals requiring special assistance. Should You require special assistance, in order to facilitate Your requirements as well as to assure the safety of our passengers and crew, Porter will need to collect and record additional information when You make Your flight arrangements (including relevant information such as to whether a wheelchair or oxygen is required or otherwise concerning Your medical condition, and emergency contact information). Such information will be forwarded to the applicable airport staff, flight crew, interlining or connecting airlines and, where Porter has outsourced certain operational functions (such as ground handling) to another airline or service provider, to such other airline or service provider.

If unaccompanied minors are travelling with Porter (in accordance with Porter’s then current unaccompanied minor policy), Porter will require and collect personal information concerning the minor child and their flight itinerary. Porter will also require the name, address and a contact telephone number of: (a) the person(s) meeting the minor child at the destination or point of transfer; (b) the parent or guardian authorizing the travel; and (c) person(s) who should be contacted in the case of an emergency. Such information will be used to facilitate the unaccompanied minors’ travel with Porter and any connecting airlines, and may be shared with the person(s) designated to meet the minor child and/or the emergency contact, as may be necessary.

### Assisting You and Information of Interest

Porter is committed to complying with CASL and other privacy laws governing the protection of Your personal information, including your email address. By booking travel through the Web Site, You are deemed to provide your consent to receive special offers, promotions and other commercial electronic messages from Porter (“Promotional Messages”). You may also subscribe to such Promotional Messages from Porter by expressly indicating your desire to receive such information (e.g. by actively clicking a ‘checkbox’ on the Web Site to receive Promotional Messages). If you have consented in one of the manners described above, Porter will provide You from time to time with information, promotions and offers Porter believes will be of interest to You. You may at any time unsubscribe from such communications by using the “unsubscribe” mechanism included at the bottom of each message. Porter will process unsubscribe requests promptly, and in any event within ten (10) business days of our receipt of the request. Because Porter is committed to respecting Your withdrawal of consent, any booking of travel following the processing of Your unsubscribe request will **not** result in a renewal of your implied consent to receive Promotional Messages.

In addition to the foregoing, Porter may use Your email address provided at the time of booking travel to send you non-commercial messages, such as itineraries, delay notifications and other operational messages, and customer satisfaction surveys.

### Applications For Employment

Porter may from time to time post employment opportunities on the Web Site or otherwise advertise such opportunities. If You would like to apply for such employment opportunities, Porter will ask for and collect Your name, address, email address, telephone number, employment history, education and other information that is relevant and related to Your application and the employment opportunity. Porter will use the information submitted to assess Your application and contact You. Porter may contact applicable third parties to verify any information submitted by You.

## AGGREGATE INFORMATION

Porter may collect aggregated, anonymous information (such as demographic and profile data, usage and selection data and similar information and data) in connection with Your use of the Web Site and the purchase of Porter services and share that information with other third parties such as Porter’s service providers, agents and advertisers, however, any such aggregated information will **not** contain personally identifiable information.

## CONSENT

When You provide Porter with Your personal information to purchase travel or to request information or other services, You are providing Porter your implied consent to collect and use Your information to fulfill the requested service or information.

If travel reservations are made through or by third parties, such as employers, travel agents or others, Porter considers them to be authorized by You to disclose personal information about You to Porter. Such collection, use and disclosure by such other persons will be subject to the privacy policies of such other persons. Porter may be further contacted or contact such other persons to the extent necessary to process and confirm booking changes and otherwise facilitate Your travel arrangements and the provision of other information and services.

Alternatively, You may from time to time, provide Porter with Your express consent to use certain information that is collected at the relevant time for the purposes that are specified at that time (e.g. to participate in surveys or promotional opportunities).

## CONFIDENTIALITY OF SUPPLIED INFORMATION

In order to protect the security and confidentiality of any personally identifiable information supplied by Porter or retained by Porter (such as booking references related to Your travel with Porter or Web Site passwords) You are responsible to ensure all such information is kept confidential by You

## RELEASE AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Except as is described in this Policy, Porter will not use and will not disclose or provide Your personal information to any person.

In some situations, Porter may use or share facilities, or engage the services of other agencies or airlines to best serve You. For example, particular airport staff may be provided with passenger lists and destinations to ensure proper routing of luggage. Porter will only release information necessary for performing the required service or provision of requested information. Also, Porter's third party service providers may have access to personal information You submit to Porter in order to perform operational or other support services on behalf of Porter (e.g. back office computer services).

Porter may disclose Your information to the extent required by law or where Porter reasonably believes it is necessary to do so to comply with law. Also, due to security requirements in Canada and other countries, Porter is required by law to collect, use and disclose to law enforcement and government regulatory and other government authorities passenger information, which may include certain of Your personal information that has been collected by Porter (in some cases such collection, use and disclosure may be made without Your knowledge or consent). In these circumstances, it is not possible for You to opt-out. Information that may be collected or shared may be more extensive than the information used to book or confirm Your travel.

Porter reserves the right to transfer any information submitted by You and retained by Porter to Porter affiliates to the extent necessary to perform requested services and provide requested information and to any third party purchasers of, or successors to, Porter's business.

## WEBSITE SECURITY

Porter will use reasonable efforts to protect Your information that You provide to Porter once it has been received by Porter. Porter uses SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology, an encryption technology used to encrypt information sent over the Internet. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while Porter strives to protect Your personal information, Porter cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information You transmit to Porter, and You do so at Your own risk.

## LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

This Policy applies only to information collected by Porter or supplied by You to Porter. Although the Web Site may provide You with links to other web sites, this Policy does not apply to those web sites or to the other collection, use or disclosure of personal information by other persons.

## USE OF ‘COOKIES’ AND BEACONS

Porter uses various technologies to passively collect information from You while You are visiting the Web Site (that is You do not actively provide this information to Porter). Such technologies allow the Web Site to collect a range of non-personally identifiable information about Your visit to and use of the Web Site. Porter typically uses such passively collected information for a variety of purposes, such as to administer the Web Site, customize the Web Site to your preferences, and compile aggregated statistics for marketing and research purposes. Porter reserves the unrestricted right to use this passively collected, non-personally identifiable information for any reason, including, but not limited to, selling, leasing, permitting access to, or otherwise transferring it to our affiliates, business partners, advertisers and other third parties.

Porter uses “cookies”. A cookie is a small data file that web sites often store on Your computer's hard drive when You visit their web site. The Web Site uses both “session cookies” and “permanent or persistent cookies”.

When You connect to the Web Site a session cookie is placed on Your computer and is removed when You log off the Web Site. These cookies help us track Your use of the Web Site each time You visit (e.g. traffic patterns concerning the sections of the Web Site that You visit and use) and help Porter to understand how we can improve Your Web Site experience. The information is collected on an anonymous and aggregate basis (i.e. it does not provide Porter any of Your personal information).

When You visit the Web Site, a persistent cookie will also be placed on Your hard drive and will remain there unless You remove them through Your browser’s Internet security settings. Permanent cookies are used to store user preferences, such as storing passwords and preferred language settings, and thus eliminate Your having to make the same entries on each visit and allows us to recognize You when You return to the Web Site and customizes Your user experience.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in Your browser. If You turn off cookies, however, it will prevent You from using certain features of the Web Site. If You are worried about the information Porter places in the cookie, You may delete permanent cookie file(s) at the end of each browser session. Your browser's help file will have instructions on how to do that.

Similarly, Porter uses conversion beacons that allows Porter to keep track of email flow between You and Porter. Conversion Beacons are short pieces of HTML computer code inserted in the source code of some website pages. These pieces of code may be inserted in an email message to You, and will result in a small type of cookie that will be stored in Your browser. It is then used to connect You as an email recipient with your later activity on Porter’s website.

## OPT OUT

If You wish to be taken off of Porter’s email list You may opt by following the steps included in every email we send, or by going to our Unsubscribe page and entering your email address.

## CONTACTING PORTER

If You have any questions or concerns about this Policy or Porter’s collection, use and disclosure of Your personal information, or to update Your information or to withdraw any consents that You have provided in the past (subject to reasonable notice, any legal requirements and similar exceptions) You may contact Porter at any time as follows:

**Address:** Greg Sheahan  
Porter Airlines Inc.  
Toronto City Centre Airport  
Toronto, Ontario   
Canada M5V 1A1 

**Telephone:** (416) 203-8100

**Fax:** (416) 203-8150

## REVISIONS TO POLICY

Porter reserves the right to modify this Policy at any time by posting an amended Policy on the Web Site. It is Your responsibility to review this Policy regularly and You are deemed to be aware of such amendments. If significant material changes are made to the Policy, Porter will use reasonable efforts to notify You of such changes on the Web Site and by such other means as Porter determines is appropriate in the circumstances.

**POLICY EFFECTIVE DATE / LAST MODIFIED: July 1, 2014**

... 

Press Escape to close the window.

Check-In using our enhanced ‘Check-In’ flow? 

You are now leaving Porter Airlines.

The external site you have chosen to view may or may not meet accessibility guidelines.

Form submission failed. There are errors in the form. 

Press tab on the keyboard to jump to the first error.
